<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE Book SYSTEM "gapdoc.dtd"
[<!ENTITY SgpViz "<Alt Not='Text'><URL
   Text='SgpViz'>https://gap-packages.github.io/sgpviz/</URL></Alt><Alt Only='Text'><Package>SgpViz</Package></Alt>">]
>

<!-- Documentation to the SgpViz package. -->

<Book Name="SgpViz">

<TitlePage>
    <Title>&SgpViz;</Title>
    <Subtitle>A &GAP; package for semigroup visualisation</Subtitle>
  <Version> Version <#Include SYSTEM "../version">
  </Version>
  <Author> Manuel Delgado
    <Email>mdelgado@fc.up.pt</Email>
    <Homepage>http://www.fc.up.pt/cmup/mdelgado</Homepage>
  </Author>
  <Author> José João Morais
  </Author>
  <Copyright>
    <Index>License</Index>
    &copyright; 2005 by Manuel Delgado and José João Morais <P/>
      <Alt Only="LaTeX">\noindent</Alt> &SgpViz; package is free software; 
      you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the 
      <URL Text="GNU General Public License">http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl.html</URL> 
      as published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the
      License, or (at your option) any later version. For details, see the file 'GPL' included in the package or see the FSF's own site.
    </Copyright>
<Colophon>
      This manual describes the &GAP; package &SgpViz;, Version <#Include SYSTEM "../version">, for visualising finite semigroups.<P/>
      <P/>
      Since Version 0.998 (released in 2008), the package is maintained by the first author.
      <P/>
      The present package is supersede by the &GAP; package <E>semigroups</E>, by James Mitchel, in what concerns some aspects of semigroup visualisation. We strongly recommend the usage of that package, unless you find useful specific tools available in &SgpViz; but not in <E>semigroups</E>. 
<P/>
Bug reports, suggestions and comments are, of course, welcome. Please use the
email address <Email>mdelgado@fc.up.pt</Email> to this effect.
<P/>

If you have benefited from the use of the &SgpViz; &GAP; package in your research, please cite it in addition to &GAP; itself, following the scheme proposed in
<URL>http://www.gap-system.org/Contacts/cite.html</URL>.

</Colophon>

<Acknowledgements>

The first author acknowledges
financial support of FCT, through the <E>Centro
de Matemática da Universidade do Porto</E>.
<P/>
The second author acknowledges financial support of FCT and the POCTI program
through a scholarship given by <E>Centro de Matemática da Universidade do Porto</E>.
<P/>
Both authors acknowledge
Jorge Almeida, Vítor H. Fernandes and Pedro Silva
for many helpful discussions and comments.
<P/>
<P/>
<B>Concerning maintenance:</B>
<P/>
<P/> The maintainer wants to acknowledge partial support by:
<P/> FCT - Fundação para a Ciência e a Tecnologia under the project PTDC/MAT/65481/2006
<P/> <E>Centro de Matemática da Universidade do Porto</E> (CMUP), funded by the European Regional Development Fund through the programme COMPETE and by the Portuguese Government through the FCT project PEst-C/MAT/UI0144/2011.
<P/>
CMUP (UID/MAT/00144/2013), which is funded by FCT (Portugal) with national (MEC) and European structural funds through the programs FEDER, under the partnership agreement PT2020.
<P/>
Furthermore, the maintainer wants to thank the organisers of <C>GAPDays</C> in their several editions, as well as several people (for advises, giving feedback, etc). Among them I would like to refer: Max Horn, James Mitchel, Jan Philipp Wächter, João Araújo, Alfredo Costa and Teresa Melo.
</Acknowledgements>

</TitlePage>

<TableOfContents/>

<Body>

<#Include SYSTEM "introduction.xml">
<#Include SYSTEM "basics.xml">
<#Include SYSTEM "drawings.xml">
<#Include SYSTEM "xsemigroup.xml">

</Body>

<Bibliography Databases="SgpViz" />

<TheIndex/>

</Book>

<!-- ==================================================================== -->
